[
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "How many times has Kirk ripped his shirt in this series?",
    "Answer 1": 10,
    "Answer 2": 5,
    "Answer 3": 13,
    "Answer 4": 8,
    "Correct Answer": 13,
    "Narrative": "Considering that there were only 79 episodes, it seems like a considerable number, doesn't it?"
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Corbomite Maneuver",
    "Question": "What organization did Balok say he represented?",
    "Answer 1": "The Fesarius",
    "Answer 2": "The First Federation",
    "Answer 3": "Cosmic Syndicate",
    "Answer 4": "Celestial Union",
    "Correct Answer": "The First Federation",
    "Narrative": "In this episode, the commander of the \"Fesarius\" was found to be a child-like alien who loved\n the beverage know as \"Tranya\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Where No Man Has Gone Before",
    "Question": "In this episode, two crew were endowed with God-like powers. Which\ntwo crew?",
    "Answer 1": "Gary Mitchell and Elizabeth \nDenher",
    "Answer 2": "Sulu and Chekov",
    "Answer 3": "Kirk and Spock",
    "Answer 4": "Scotty and McCoy",
    "Correct Answer": "Gary Mitchell and Elizabeth \nDenher",
    "Narrative": "The two crew were endowed with God-like powers due to a force field that the Enterprise passed\nthrough. Mitchell became power-mad, while Dehner was able to control her response."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Naked Time",
    "Question": "Crewman Kevin Riley barricaded himself in Engineering and repatedly\nsang the song \"I'll Take You Home Again Kathleen\". Which of these\nsingers also performed this song?",
    "Answer 1": "Elvis Presley",
    "Answer 2": "Dean Martin",
    "Answer 3": "Jerry Lee Lewis",
    "Answer 4": "Tom Jones",
    "Correct Answer": "Elvis Presley",
    "Narrative": "This song was included on Elvis Presley's album \"Fool\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "City on the Edge of Forever",
    "Question": "What drug did Doctor McCoy accidentally inject himself with in\nthis episode",
    "Answer 1": "Cordrazine",
    "Answer 2": "Tri-Ox",
    "Answer 3": "Hyronalin",
    "Answer 4": "Leporazine",
    "Correct Answer": "Cordrazine",
    "Narrative": "This drug, when given in large amount s, can cause serious mental instability. In this case, it caused McCoy to go\ntemporarily insane which ultimately made him jump through the \"Guardian of Forever\" into Earth's past."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Doomsday Machine",
    "Question": "In this episode, what happened to Commodore Decker's crew?",
    "Answer 1": "They transported to the surface\n of a planet",
    "Answer 2": "They abondoned ship in\nescape pods",
    "Answer 3": "They transported to another\nship",
    "Answer 4": "They stayed onboard",
    "Correct Answer": "They transported to the surface\n of a planet",
    "Narrative": "They crew transported to the surface of the planet that Decker's ship was orbiting. Ultimately, the Doomsday\nMachine destroyed the planet, resulting in the death of Decker's entire crew."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Catspaw",
    "Question": "In this episode, two aliens took human form and had magical powers.\nWhat device gave them this ability?",
    "Answer 1": "Transmuter",
    "Answer 2": "Universal modulator",
    "Answer 3": "Dimensional alterator",
    "Answer 4": "Cosmic resonator",
    "Correct Answer": "Transmuter",
    "Narrative": "This device was used by \"Sylvia\" to transform herself into a cat, and into a woman. Sylvia and Korob were actually creatures\nthat could not survive the conditions on the planet without the Transmuter, and they ultimately died when Kirk destroyed it."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "A Piece of the Action",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk teaches his captors a fictional card game. What\nwas the name of this game?",
    "Answer 1": "Stellar Flush",
    "Answer 2": "Fizbin",
    "Answer 3": "Galactic Bluff",
    "Answer 4": "Cosmic Poker",
    "Correct Answer": "Fizbin",
    "Narrative": "In this ridiculous game, some of the rules are: The second card is turned up, except on Tuesdays, If the player gets 2 Jacks, they get\nanother card \"if it's dark outside\", and the best cards to get are a King and Queen, except at night, when you want a Queen and\na Jack."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Specter of the Gun",
    "Question": "In this episode, what was the name of the alien species the crew of\nthe Enterprise encountered?",
    "Answer 1": "Romulans",
    "Answer 2": "Melkotions",
    "Answer 3": "Metrons",
    "Answer 4": "Talosians",
    "Correct Answer": "Melkotions",
    "Narrative": "The \"Melkots\", as a result of the Enterprise crew ignoring a warning not to approach their planet, caused the landing party to\nparticipate in a deadly \"Shootout at the O.K. Corral\" simulation."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Miri",
    "Question": "In this episode, the crew encounters children who, when they reach\nadulthood turn into what the children call what?",
    "Answer 1": "Grups",
    "Answer 2": "Oldies",
    "Answer 3": "Ageds",
    "Answer 4": "Adulties",
    "Correct Answer": "Grups",
    "Narrative": "Obviously a warped version of \"grown-ups\". The inhabitants of an almost identical Earth planet attempted to create immortality,\nand instead killed all of the adults, but kept the children young for hundreds of years. In the end, once they did reach adulthood,\nthey also died quickly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Shore Leave",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk finds someone from his Starfleet Acadamy days,\nand has a prolonged fight with him. Who is this person?",
    "Answer 1": "Finnegan",
    "Answer 2": "Gary Mitchell",
    "Answer 3": "Ben Finney",
    "Answer 4": "Carol Marcus",
    "Correct Answer": "Finnegan",
    "Narrative": "An \"upper-classman\", Finnegan tormented Kirk in his acadamy days. In this episode, Kirk gets a chance to \"get even\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Squire of Gothos",
    "Question": "In this episode, Kirk and his landing party encounter an alien\nentity who claims to have studied Earth's past. Who is this alien?",
    "Answer 1": "Vina",
    "Answer 2": "Trelane",
    "Answer 3": "Flint",
    "Answer 4": "Sargon",
    "Correct Answer": "Trelane",
    "Narrative": "Although Trelane appears to be a powerful alien, with powers that are almost magical, he is later found to be an immature\nmember of a powerful species, and treats his \"pets\" and \"toys\" poorly."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "The Changeling",
    "Question": "In this episode, \"Nomad\" has incorrectly idenfied Kirk as its creator.\nKirk has to destroy Nomad before it destroys the Enterprise. How does\nKirk accomplish this?",
    "Answer 1": "Confuses Nomad with logic",
    "Answer 2": "Tricks Nomad into \"beaming\"\ninto a star",
    "Answer 3": "Uploaded a virus into Nomad",
    "Answer 4": "Generated a strong\nmagnetic field into Nomad.",
    "Correct Answer": "Confuses Nomad with logic",
    "Narrative": "Because Nomad has mistakenly identified Kirk as \"The Kirk\", his creator, and Nomad values \"perfection\", Kirk is able to\ncause Nomad to destroy itself as a result of its \"imperfection\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Dr. Richard Daystrom introduced M5, a new computer on the\nEnterprise. What type of computer was this?",
    "Answer 1": "Multitronic",
    "Answer 2": "Duotronic",
    "Answer 3": "Bio-Neural",
    "Answer 4": "Positronic",
    "Correct Answer": "Multitronic",
    "Narrative": "Multitronic computers become the future of computing in Star Trek. They were a significant improvement from the\nprevious Duotronic computer systems. Of course, this doesn't occur until well after the self-preservation and destroying of\nother Starfleet vessel issues were ironed out."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "How many times does Doctor McCoy claim, \"I'm a Doctor, not a....\"?",
    "Answer 1": 5,
    "Answer 2": 10,
    "Answer 3": 20,
    "Answer 4": 11,
    "Correct Answer": 11,
    "Narrative": "11 times in 79 episodes. That's pretty significant. He has claimed not to be a bricklayer, an escalator and an engineer, \namong other things."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "What was another name for the Pon Farr, that caused Vulcans to\nmate or die?",
    "Answer 1": "Hot blood",
    "Answer 2": "Blood fever",
    "Answer 3": "Death curse",
    "Answer 4": "Mating fever",
    "Correct Answer": "Blood fever",
    "Narrative": "In Amok Time, Spock must mate or die. That sucks."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Particles",
    "Question": "What did the \"Doomsday Machine\" use to destroy planets?",
    "Answer 1": "Antiproton beam",
    "Answer 2": "Antimatter beam",
    "Answer 3": "Antineutron beam",
    "Answer 4": "Antithoron beam",
    "Correct Answer": "Antiproton beam",
    "Narrative": "Commodore Decker described the beam fired from the Doomsday Machine as antiprotons - \"Absolutely pure\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Planets",
    "Question": "In which star system is the planet Vulcan located?",
    "Answer 1": "40 Eridani",
    "Answer 2": "Tau Ceti",
    "Answer 3": "Wolf 359",
    "Answer 4": "Barnard's star",
    "Correct Answer": "40 Eridani",
    "Narrative": "This is actually a real star system, located approximately 16.5 light years from earth."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "General Orders",
    "Question": "General order 7 prohibits travel to which planet?",
    "Answer 1": "Talos IV",
    "Answer 2": "Ceti Alpha V",
    "Answer 3": "40 Eridani",
    "Answer 4": "Ceti Alpha IV",
    "Correct Answer": "Talos IV",
    "Narrative": "Due to the Talosians ability to telepathically induce hallucinations and make people believe what is not true, Starfleet\ninstituted General Order 7, prohibiting travel to that planet \"for any reason\"."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Who played Spock's father and also a Romulan Commander?",
    "Answer 1": "Mark Lenard",
    "Answer 2": "Morgan Woodward",
    "Answer 3": "Barbara Babcock",
    "Answer 4": "William Campbell",
    "Correct Answer": "Mark Lenard",
    "Narrative": "Although all of these actors have played multiple roles in Star Trek: The Original Series, Lenard was Spock's father and also portrayed\nthe Romulan Commander in the episode Balance of Terror."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Planets",
    "Question": "Who inhabits the planet Holberg 917G?",
    "Answer 1": "Flint",
    "Answer 2": "Harry Mudd",
    "Answer 3": "Zephram Cochrane",
    "Answer 4": "Trelane",
    "Correct Answer": "Flint",
    "Narrative": "Flint was an immortal human who claimed to also be Mozart, and a number of other significant people in Earth's history."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What species language is problematic for the universal translator?",
    "Answer 1": "Romulan",
    "Answer 2": "Tholian",
    "Answer 3": "Metrons",
    "Answer 4": "Talosians",
    "Correct Answer": "Tholian",
    "Narrative": "The universal translator had difficulty with the Tholians language, perhaps due to their unique structure."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Character",
    "Question": "Which crew was an accomplished singer and dancer prior to\nappearing in Star Trek?",
    "Answer 1": "Uhura",
    "Answer 2": "Spock",
    "Answer 3": "Sulu",
    "Answer 4": "McCoy",
    "Correct Answer": "Uhura",
    "Narrative": "Prior to her appearing as Uhura, Nichelle Nichols was an accomplished singer and dancer."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What keeps a photon torpedo from exploding prematurely?",
    "Answer 1": "Magnetic containment field",
    "Answer 2": "Quantum field containment",
    "Answer 3": "Temporal shielding",
    "Answer 4": "Subspace interlocks",
    "Correct Answer": "Magnetic containment field",
    "Narrative": "Photon torpedos are armed with matter and antimatter, seperated by a magnetic containment field. Once the containment\nfield is removed, the torpedo explodes."
  },
  {
    "Series / Movie": "The Original Series",
    "Description": "Technology",
    "Question": "What does dilithium do in propulsion systems?",
    "Answer 1": "Stabilize and focus matter and\nantimatter",
    "Answer 2": "Provides fuel for the warp\ndrive",
    "Answer 3": "Cools the matter/antimatter\ncontainment chamber",
    "Answer 4": "Creates a warp field",
    "Correct Answer": "Stabilize and focus matter and\nantimatter",
    "Narrative": "Dilithium acts as a stabilizer for the warp engines by focusing the matter/antimatter reaction to contain the massive energy\noutput necessary for warp propulsion."
  }
]